Hussain Fathi . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent Electrical and Biomedical Engineering graduate from McMaster University. I'm currently working as a Data Engineer at Jarvis Consulting, taking part in multiple projects such as the Linux Cluster Usage Administration, Java Grepp and Java Twitter apps. In addition to Jarvis, I'm also currently working as a Software Engineer at a startup company based in Toronto. My role is centered around designing, developing, and testing an enterprise-level platform targeted towards helping international startup companies to enter the North American markets. Throughout my undergraduate career, I have completed 16 months worth of internship experiences in the fields of Machine Learning and Software development at the Department of National Defence in Ottawa and Adlib Software. I'm really passionate about computer science because it can also be employed in our daily lives.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Node.js, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Python, Keras, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Docker

Familiar: Google Cloud Platform, .NET framework, React, Express.js, Angular

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_HussainFathi

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Designed, developed, and tested a Linux cluster usage administration agent that allows the user to analyze the usage data of different machines that are connected together through a network switch. A PSQL docker container was employed in this project in order to store the machine's usage and hardware data that are obtained by executing two different bash scripts. Crontab was used to retrieve the machine's usage data every one minute and insert it into the PostgreSQL database. Finally, multiple SQL queries can be executed to analyze the data.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]: In progress! Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Athletic Tracking Assistant | Final Year Capstone Project: Designed and built a smart video capturing device that follows a target throughout a training session or a game in order to provide real-time athletic performance. The project was awarded the best electronic hardware device by the Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) Department.

Professional Experiences

Data Engineer, Jarvis (2021-present): Took part in an Agile work environment as a data engineer and lead various sprint meetings. Implemented various software projects employing a wide range of technologies such as Java, SQL, Docker, Git and Bash.

Software Engineer, LatAm Startups (2021-present): Participated in internal and customer-driven design reviews to discuss the functionalities that need to be incorporated into the platform. Employed MEAN stack technologies to develop an enterprise platform from client to server to database.

Software Engineer Intern, Department of National Defence (2020): Worked in the Radar Electronic Warfare (REW) team within the Defense Research and Development Canada agency (DRDC) which is aimed to provide the Canadian Armed Forces with modern radar detection technology. Employed advanced signal processing techniques and machine learning tools such as neural networks, random forest, and Support Vector Machines (SVM) to classify different categories of cognitive radars.

Software Developer Intern, Adlib Software (2019): Worked in an interdisciplinary Agile team environment and interacted with Business Analysts, Product Owners, and other stakeholders regularly to discuss new product requirements and specifications. Took part in back-end development and front-end web development to implement new functionalities to the enterprise software.

Education

McMaster University (2016-2021), Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Biomedical Engineering - Granted enrollment in the Biomedical Program due to highly competitive first year grades. - GPA: 3.3/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Best electronic hardware device awarded by the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department (ECE) at Mc-Master University for the final year capstone project.
- Volunteer, VP Media @ McMaster Planetary Society (2019-2020): Worked in a team of 7 other executive members to promote, plan and host space related events to McMaster University students.